Guide to the Time Inc. Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) Records 1985 MS 3009-RG 54
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) Records
1985
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 54
1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) was a company owned by Time Inc. that produced reports on the sale of consumer goods and offered them for sale by subscription. The collection consists of examples of these reports and correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts. Restricted materials are located in box R86.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically based on the original arrangement.
Historical Note
Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) was founded by J. Clarke Mattimore, a consultant in the Time-Life Broadcast division, in 1965 to measure the sale of products by tracking inventory in wholesale warehouses. Reports produced from this information were offered for sale by subscription to consumer-goods manufacturing companies. Time Inc. Sold SAMI in 1987.
Citations:
Associated Press. "Time Will Sell SAMI-Burke to Control Data." Los Angeles Times, 14 Oct. 1987, www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1987-10-14-fi-9248-story.html.
Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980. New York: Atheneum.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of reports on product re-stocking at retail warehouses and correspondence with paying subscribers to these reports.
Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Marketing research; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Nutribevco: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 1)
- Olin: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 2)
- The Perrier Group: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 3)
- The Perrier Group: Correspondence [Restricted], 1995 (Offsite-box R86, Folder 93)
- The Perrier Group: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 4)
- Pfizer: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 5)
- Pfizer: Scans, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 6)
- Progresso: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 7)
- Progresso: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 8)
- Refined Syrups and Sugars: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 9)
- Sau-Sea Foods: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 10)
- Thompson Medical: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 11)
- Thompson Medical: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 12)
- Union Carbide Corporation: Battery Products Division: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 13)
- Union Carbide Corporation: Battery Products Division: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 14)
- Union Carbide Corporation: Home Products Division: Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 15)
- Union Carbide Corporation: Home Products Division: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 16)
- Warner-Lambert: American Chicle Division: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 17)
- Warner-Lambert: American Chicle Division: General Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 18)
- Warner-Lambert: American Chicle Division: Scans, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 19)
- Warner-Lambert: Antacids, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 20)
- Warner-Lambert: Breath Fresheners, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 21)
- Warner-Lambert: Bubble Gum, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 22)
- Warner-Lambert: Consumer Health Products: Distribution, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 23)
- Warner-Lambert: Consumer Health Products: General Correspondence, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 24)
- Warner-Lambert: Consumer Health Products: Supermarkets, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 25)
- Warner-Lambert: Cough Syrups, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 26)
- Warner-Lambert: Loose Candy, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 27)
- Warner-Lambert: Razor Blades, 1985 (Offsite-box 4094, Folder 28)